KELVIN NGURE

Nairobi, Kenya ngure.kelvin@live.com+254 724 634 854 linkedin.com/in/kelvin-mwaniki-11948b238 https://github.com/Kelvinfox1

Summary

A highly organized, analytical, dependable, and detail-oriented Software Engineer with a strong background of accurate and efficient software creation activities for a diverse range of clientele.

4+ years of industry experience includes leading successful start-ups to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline.

Possess a strong theoretical and practical knowledge of Software Development, Test automation, Database management, User Interface design.

Experience

Data Specialist

TRANSFORM RESEARCH AFRICA

Apr 2017 - Apr 2019 (2 years 1 month)

• Took part in Data entry, team supervision on a part time basis for the organization, worked on research projects from Diageo plc (Guinness manufacturers), conducted in Ethiopia, Ghana, Nigeria and Kenya.

Software Engineer

Circularity Space

Jan 2019 - May 2022 (3 years 5 months)

- Tasked with Software Design and Implementation of user application for reward of points on every disposal redeemable for cash or discount of Product. This helped incentivise people on waste recycling Integrated deep learning algorithm for image recognition using Arduino sensors that saw the on boarding of Coca Cola Bottling Company Embakasi as partners in the piloting stage
- · Worked on backup and recovery strategies using RMAN
- Exported full schema, tablespace and object level
- · Refreshing and cloning database from production to development using RMAN and OS level scripts
- Through pitch decks, we were able to emerge second runners up at the Hult prize start-up challenge.

Software Engineer

SBO Research Ltd

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- Designed and developed a new Integrated Operations Platform tool through Agile
 Methodologies, ReactJs, NodeJs and Firebase to efficiently collect, analyse and visualize raw data
 resulting in an increase of company revenue
- Proficiently troubleshot simple to complex technological issues for the assigned projects, achieving over 90% customer satisfaction rate
- Responsible for developing different databases at various stages of implementation of Projects
- Migration of existing SQL user data to No-SQL architecture that saw reduced overhead time on consecutive API calls
- Documented all supported systems and application to effectively train new and existing members

Software Engineer

myNGOVO

Jan 2022 - Present (8 months +)

- Built a resume builder, resume review AI, resume benchmark Web Application with multiple payment APIs that saw a 30% increase in company revenue
- Developed and deployed a modern user interface of the company website to improve user experience
 Utilized software engineering techniques to develop product through the software life cycle to boost business efficiency, from idealization and requirement through to development and successful deployment
- Installed, configured and maintained oracle database on Linux and Solaris environment
- Created user database as per requirement using DBCA and scripts
- Start-up and Shutdown of individual instances on RAC 2 node environment
- Created Database object like Tables, Table spaces, Rollback Segments, Multiplexing Control files,
 Data files, Implemented scripts to help rollout and managed Oracle in a global distributed environment

Environment

 Oracle 9i, 10g, 11g, RMAN, Solaris, Linux, HP-AX, VMware, UNIX Shell Scripting, Import and Export Datapump

Education

Multimedia University of Kenya

Software Engineering, Bachelor's degree

2016 - 2021

Relevant Courses: Software Project management, Distributed Systems Development, Information Systems Modelling, Specification of Software Systems, Software Evolution, Software Quality, Agile Methods

Skills

```
Software Development • Test Automation • Machine Learning • Web Development • API

Development • JavaScript • Debugging • Data Structures • SQL • Docker Products • Design •

Adobe Photoshop • User Experience • Driving • Database Management • Innovator • Oracle

Enterprise Manager
```

Honors & Awards

2021 Hult Prize regional winners - Hult Prize Foundation

Mar 2021

Together with Virdismart team we pitched an impact-full project on waste recycle and made it to number one